Guide to the Henry Barnard Papers 1765-1935 (Bulk 1830-1899) MSS.033
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Subseries A: Barnard's Letters to Family and Associates, 1833-1900
    - To Barnard, Chauncey, 1833-1835; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - To Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1853-1856 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - To Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1857-1860 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - To Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1861-1865 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - To Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1866-1882 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - To Monroe, Will, 1892-1900 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - To Potter, E.R., 1845-1846 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - To Potter, E.R., 1847-1848 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - To Potter, E.R., 1849-1852 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - To Potter, E.R., 1853-1857 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - To Potter, E.R., 1858-1869 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - To Potter, E.R., 1870-1875 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - To Potter, E.R., 1876-1882 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - To Various Others, 1840-1859 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      General note
      Includes letters to Goerge Barnard Jr. (no. 1 in folder), Josiah Holbrook (no. 2 in folder), S.W. Walley Jr. (no. 3 in folder), Walter Ferguson (no. 4 in folder), Jesse Olney (no. 6 in folder), Noah W. Hoyt (no. 7 in folder), Mr. Doolittle (no. 8 in folder), Mr. Gillett (no. 9 in folder), Charles H. Palmer (no. 10 in folder), David Read (no. 11 in folder), [F.A.P.Barnard] (12), G.E. Billings (no. 14 in folder), J.F. Griggs (no. 15 in folder), R.M. Johnson (no. 18 in folder), Ezra S. Carr (no. 19 in folder), Mr. Perkins, Horace Mann, Mr. Montgomery, and four unknown
    - To Various Others, 1860-1869 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Includes letters to R.R. Boutwright (1), Mr. Perkins (2), "Seymour" (3, 6), Mr.Burgess (4, 5), Henry E. Sawyer (8), Alfred S. Kennedy (9), W. Sharswood (12), Executive Council of St. John's College (13), John Thompson Mason (15), N. Brewer (16, 20), Alexander Vattemore (17), [Jno] L. Smithmyer (18), J. Donnelly (21), Westerman & Co. (23), Alphonse Leroy (24), Heavily annotated leaflet "Ten Planks in the Common School Platform" (25), Letter of Introduction for F. Barham Zinche (26), Andrew Johnson (28), J.D. Cox (31-32, 36), H.H. Tucker (33-35), Dr. Jackson (37), John Kraus (38), and eight unknowns
    - To Various Others, 1870-1879 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Includes two letters to unknown individuals
    - To Various Others, 1880-1900 (Bulk: 1880-1889) (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Includes letters to C.J Hoadley, John W. Stedamn, and John F. Morris (1-2, typed copies?), J.D. Giddings (3,4), Mr. [Trumbull] (5), ["Brother Andrew"] (6), Annie M. Kellogg (7), Leslie Stephen (10, typed), George P. Phenix (11), Aaron Grove (12, typed), Thomas Stockwell (13, typed), Mr. Camp (14, typed), Emily Mason (15, typed), James L. Hughes (16, 25, typed), Mr. Russell (17, typed), Mr. [John] Hooker (18, typed), Fannibelle Curtis (19, typed), Mrs. O'Brien (20, typed), [Mary] Snow (21, typed), Miss Wheelock (22, typed), [George] Plimpton (23, t), Mr. Hill (24, t), Committee for the Westfield Normal School: Bertha E. Emmons, Grace M. Dana, and Emma Gilbert (26, t), Miss Bancroft (27, t), A.D. Mayo (28), Lucinda T. Guilford (30, photocopy of original held by Mount Holyoke College Library), Mr. Dawson (31), F.A.P. Barnard (32), Charles Marseilles (33), and three unknowns
    - To Various Others, 1890-1900 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Includes letters to Charles Northend (1), A.G. Young (3, t, dictated), [Charles] Marseilles (4, 9, t,d), Dr. Harris (7, photocopy, original absent, 24), R.H. Quick (8), Mr. [Trumbull] (10), 11-19 absent, Mr [Thomas]Cushing (20), article "Dr. Barnard's Greetings to the Kindergarten" a letter by Barnard to a kindergarten in Tennessee printed in Alfred E. Winship's Journal of Education (21), Mr. Tillinghast (22, d,t,), Mr. Kellogg (23), H.S. Gulliver (25-26), Foster Watson (27), C.J. Hoodley (28, 30, t), [Felix] Heikel (29, t), [Mr. Flynt] (31), and three unknowns.
    - To Various Others, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Includes letters to a cousin, [Frank E. King] (2), Mr. Perkins (3), and one unknown.
  - Subseries B: Letters to Barnard Arranged by Correspondent, 1831-1900
    - From Barnard Family: C.F., D.D., Elizabeth, Henry Jr., Horace, Linda, Louise, 1835-1891 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - From Barnard, Chauncey Jr. and Son, 1831-1865 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Also includes letters from Chauncey Barnard to John Barnard, to Henry Barnard's Father (Chauncey Barnard Sr.), and to Roland Sanford
    - From Barnard, F.A.P., 1855-185[8] (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - From Barnard, F.A.P., 1858-1863 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - From Barnard, F.A.P., 1864-1887 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - From Barnard, Josephine, 1848-1888 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - From Beecher, Catherine E., 1845-1864 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - From Corson, Hiram, 1866-1871 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - From Edwards, Richard, 1856-1865 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Bloomington, Ind.; St. Louis, MO
    - From Eliot, Samuel, 1860-1866; Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - From Emerson, George, B., 1841-1877 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Boston, MA
    - From Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - From Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1853-1854 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - From Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1855-1856 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - From Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1857-1858 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - From Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1859-1860 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - From Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1861-1865 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - From Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1866-1876 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - From Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1878-1893; Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - From Mann, Horace and Mary, 1856-1860 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - From Mann, Horace and Mary, 1861-1869 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - From Mann, Mary, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - From Monroe, Will, 1893-1900; Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - From Philbrick, John D., 1847-1858 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - From Philbrick, John D., 1859-1861 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - From Philbrick, John D., 1862-1864 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - From Philbrick, John D., 1865-1868 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - From Philbrick, John D., 1869-1889 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - From Wells, William H., 1841-1849 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Boston, etc
    - From Wells, William H., 1850-1860 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - From Wells, William H., 1861-1865 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - From Wells, William H., 1866-1885 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Subseries C: Letters, Primarily to Barnard, 1765-1899.
    Folder 121-A, 230, 231 contain correspondence not included in Index.
    - no. 6, 11, 1765-1832 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - no. 1-5, 7-10, 12-33, 1765-1833 (Box 2, Folder 1A)
    - no. 34-71, 1833-1834 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - no. 72-110, 1835-1836 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - no. 111-130, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - no. 131-171, 1838, Jan.-Sep. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - no. 172-200, 1838, Oct.-Nov. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - no. 201-222, 1838-1839, Nov.-Jan. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - no. 223-248, 1839, Jan.-Feb. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - no. 249-271, 1839, Mar.-Apr. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - no. 272-288, 1839, May-Jun. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - no. 289-304, 1839, Jul.-Aug. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - no. 305-328, 1839, Sep.-Oct. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - no. 329-354, 1839, Nov.-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - no. 355-386, 1840, Jan.-Mar. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - no. 387-424, 1840, Apr.-May (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - no. 425-452, 1840, Jun.-Sep. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - no. 453-472, 1840, Oct.-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - no. 473-520, 1841, Jan.-Mar. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - no. 521-547, 1841, Apr.-Jun. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - no. 548-566, 1841, Jul.-Sep. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - no. 567-601, 1841, Oct.-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - no. 602-630, 1842, Jan.-Feb. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - no. 631-675, 1842, Mar.-May (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - no. 676-723, 1842, Jun.-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - no. 724-748, 1843, Jan.-Jun. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - no. 749-787, 1843, Jul.-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - no. 788-814, 1844, Jan.-Mar. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - no. 815-848, 1844, Apr.-Jun. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - no. 849-872, 1844, Jul.-Sep. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - no. 873-904, 1844, Oct.-Dec. (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - no. 905-936, 1845, Jan.-Feb. (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - no. 937-964, 1845, Mar.-Apr. (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - no. 965-992, 1845, May-Jun. (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - no. 993-1019, 1845, Jul.-Aug. (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - no. 1020-1045, 1845, Sep.-Oct. (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - no. 1046-1111, 1845, Nov.-Dec. (Box 3, Folder 36)
      For item 1077 see Series IV, Box 9, Folder 5
    - no. 1112-1139, 1846, Jan. (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - no. 1140-1187, 1846, Feb.-Mar. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - no. 1188-1224, 1846, Apr.-May (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - no. 1225-1266, 1846, Jun.-Jul. (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - no. 1267-1298, 1846, Aug. (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - no. 1299-1334, 1846, Sep. (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - no. 1335-1389, 1846, Oct.-Nov. (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - no. 1390-1440, 1846, Dec. (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - no. 1441-1477, 1847, Jan. (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - no. 1478-1505, 1847, Feb. (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - no. 1506-1540, 1847, Mar. (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - no. 1541-1578, 1847, Apr.-May (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - no. 1579-1601, 1847, Jun. (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - no. 1602-1627, 1847, Jul. (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - no. 1628-1659, 1847, Aug. (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - no. 1660-1712, 1847, Sep.-Oct. (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - no. 1713-1753, 1847, Nov. (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - no. 1754-1795, 1847, Dec. (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - no. 1796-1848, 1848, Jan.-Feb. (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - no. 1849-1898, 1848, Mar.-Apr. (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - no. 1899-1937, 1848, May-Jun. (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - no. 1938-1977, 1848, Jul. (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - no. 1978-2027, 1848, Aug.-Sep. (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - no. 2028-2073, 1848, Oct. (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - no. 2074-2109, 1848, Nov. (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - no. 2110-2142, 1848, Dec. (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - no. 2143-2166, 1849, Jan. (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - no. 2167-2190, 1849, Feb. (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - no. 2191-2225, 1849, Mar.-Apr. (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - no. 2226-2258, 1849, May-Jul. (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - no. 2259-2297, 1849, Aug.-Sep. (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - no. 2298-2336, 1849, Oct. (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - no. 2337-2363, 1849, Nov. (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - no. 2364-2393, 1849, Dec. (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - no. 2394-2423, 1850, Jan. (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - no. 2424-2464, 1850, Feb.-Mar. (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - no. 2465-2514, 1850, Apr.-May (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - no. 2515-2555, 1850, Jun.-Jul. (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - no. 2556-2599, 1850, Aug.-Sep. (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - no. 2600-2626, 1850, Oct. (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - no. 2627-2661, 1850, Nov. (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - no. 2662-2721, 1850, Dec. (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - no. 2722-2763, 1851, Jan.-Apr. (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - no. 2764-2801, 1851, May-Jul. (Box 4, Folder 80)
      For item 2-2787 See Series IV, Box 9, Folder 1
    - no. 2802-2841, 1851, Aug.-Sep. (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - no. 2842-2900, 1851, Oct.-Dec. (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - no. 2901-2944, 1852, Jan.-Mar. (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - no. 2945-3001, 1852, Apr.-Jun. (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - no. 3002-3056, 1852, Jul.-Sep. (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - no. 3057-3134, 1852, Oct.-Dec. (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - no. 3135-3185, 1853, Jan.-Feb. (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - no. 3186-3227, 1853, Mar.-May (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - no. 3228-3294, 1853, Jun.-Sep. (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - no. 3295-3370, 1853, Oct.-Dec. (Box 4, Folder 90)
      For item 3344 See Series IV, Box 9, Folder 6
    - no. 3371-3424, 1854, Jan.-Mar. (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - no. 3425-3478, 1854, Apr.-Jun. (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - no. 3479-3527, 1854, Jul.-Sep. (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - no. 3528-3575, 1854, Oct.-Dec. (Box 4, Folder 94)
      For item 2-3574 See Series IV, Box 9, Folder 1
    - no. 3576-3640, 1855, Jan.-Mar. (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - no. 3641-3694, 1855, Apr.-Jun. (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - no. 3695-3758, 1855, Jul.-Sep. (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - no.3759-3858, 1855, Oct.-Dec. (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - no. 3859-3927, 1856, Jan. (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - no. 3928-3981, 1856, Feb. (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - no. 3982-4085, 1856, Mar.-Apr. (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - no. 4056-4173, 1856, May-Jun. (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - no. 4174-4271, 1856, Jul.-Sep. (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - no. 4272-4387, 1856, Oct.-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - no. 4388-4472, 1857, Jan.-Feb. (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - no. 4473-4527, 1857 Mar. (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - no. 4528-4604, 1857, Apr.-May (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - no. 4605-4671, 1857, Jun.-Jul. (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - no. 4672-4742, 1857, Aug.-Oct. (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - no. 4743-4812, 1857, Nov.-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - no. 4813-4864, 1858, Jan. (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - no. 4865-4941, 1858, Feb.-Mar. (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - no. 4942-5010, 1858, Apr.-May (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - no.5011-5087, 1858, Jun.-Jul. (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - no. 5088-5186, 1858, Aug.-Sep. (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - no. 5187-5256, 1858, Oct.-Nov. (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - no. 5257-5317, 1858, Dec. (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - no. 5318-5383, 1859, Jan.-Feb. (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - no. 5384-5428, 1859, Mar. (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - no. 5429-5487, 1859, Apr.-May (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - no. 5488-5526, 1859, Jun. (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - Letters from faculty members at the University of Wisconsin, 1859, Jun. (Box 5, Folder 121-A)
      Includes letters written by Daniel Reid, D.H. Lathrop, J.W. Sterling, Ezra S. Carr, J. L Pickard, James D. Butler, J.T. Clark, and J.D. Ruggles
    - no. 5527-5567, 1859, Jul. (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - no. 5568-5619, 1859, Aug. (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - no. 5620-5676, 1859, Sep. (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - no. 5677-5733, 1859, Oct. (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - no. 5734-5784, 1859, Nov. (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - no. 5785-5847, 1859, Dec. (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - no. 5848-5915, 1860, Jan.-Feb. (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - no. 5916-5964, 1860, Mar. (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - no. 5965-6006, 1860, Apr. (Box 5, Folder 130)
    - no. 6007-6069, 1860, May-Jun. (Box 5, Folder 131)
    - no. 6070-6098, 1860, Jul. (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - no. 6099-6149, 1860, Aug.-Sep. (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - no. 6150-6221, 1860, Oct.-Nov. (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - no. 6222-6264, 1860, Dec. (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - no. 6265-6289, 1860? Undated (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - no. 6290-6333, 1861, Jan.-Feb. (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - no. 6334-6402, 1861, Mar.-May (Box 6, Folder 138)
      Includes one letter from [Mrs. A.] Greene that are out of chronological order and have no alphabetical index numbers, located between items 6392 and 6393
    - no. 6403-6432, 1861, Jun.-Aug. (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - no. 6433-6477, 1861, Jun.-Jul. (Box 6, Folder 140)
    - no. 6478-6524, 1861, Nov.-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 141)
    - no. 6525-6578, 1862, Jan.-Feb. (Box 6, Folder 142)
    - no. 6579-6649, 1862, Mar.-Apr. (Box 6, Folder 143)
      Includes three letters from [Mrs. A.] Greene that are out of chronological order and have no alphabetical index numbers, located between items 6606 and 6607
    - no. 6650-6720, 1862, May-Jul. (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - no. 6721-6791, 1862, Aug.-Oct. (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - no. 6792-6860, 1862, Nov.-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 146)
    - no. 6861-6919, 1863, Jan.-Apr. (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - no. 6920-6981, 1863, May-Sep. (Box 6, Folder 148)
    - no. 6982-7048, 1863, Oct.-Nov. (Box 6, Folder 149)
    - no. 7049-7068, 1863, Dec. (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - no. 7069-7133, 1864, Jan. (Box 6, Folder 151)
    - no. 7134-7201, 1864, Feb. (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - no. 7202-7258, 1864, Mar. (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - no. 7259-7322, 1864, Apr.-May (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - no. 7323-7375, 1864, Jun.-Sep. (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - no. 7376-7459, 1864, Oct.-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 156)
    - no. 7460-7553, 1865, Jan.-Feb. (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - no. 7554-7681, 1865, Mar.- May (Box 6, Folder 158)
    - no. 7682-7780, 1865, Jun.-Jul. (Box 6, Folder 159)
    - no. 7781-7811, 1865, Aug. (Box 6, Folder 160)
    - no. 7812-7853, 1865, Sep. (Box 6, Folder 161)
    - no. 7854-7978, 1865, Oct.-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 162)
    - no. 7979-7992, 1865; Undated (Box 6, Folder 163)
    - no. 7993-8082, 1866, Jan.-Feb. (Box 6, Folder 164)
    - no. 8083-8171, 1866, Mar.-Apr. (Box 6, Folder 165)
    - no. 8172-8269, 1866, May-Jul. (Box 6, Folder 166)
    - no. 8270-8359, 1866, Aug.-Oct. (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - no. 8360-8436, 1866, Nov.-Dec; Undated (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - no. 8437-8501, 1867, Jan.-Mar. (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - no. 8502-8569, 1867, Apr.-Jun. (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - no. 8570-8658, 1867, Jul.-Aug. (Box 7, Folder 171)
    - no. 8659-8709, 1867, Sep. (Box 7, Folder 172)
    - no. 8710-8762, 1867, Oct. (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - no. 8763-8819, 1867, Nov. (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - no. 8820-8913, 1867, Dec.; Undated (Box 7, Folder 175)
    - no. 8914-8976, 1868, Jan. (Box 7, Folder 176)
    - no. 8977-9033, 1868, Feb. (Box 7, Folder 177)
    - no. 9034-9136, 1868, Mar.-May (Box 7, Folder 178)
    - no. 9137-9236, 1868, Jun.-Sep. (Box 7, Folder 179)
    - no. 9237-9294, 1868, Oct.-Dec.; Undated (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - no. 9295-9340, 1869, Jan.-Jun. (Box 7, Folder 181)
    - no. 9341-9397, 1869, Jul.-Dec. (Box 7, Folder 182)
    - no. 9398-9449, 1870 (Box 7, Folder 183)
      Item 9400 is clipped to 9398
    - no. 9450-9516, 1871 (Box 7, Folder 184)
    - no. 9517-9564, 1872 (Box 7, Folder 185)
    - no. 9565-9642, 1873 (Box 7, Folder 186)
    - no. 9643-9679, 1874 (Box 7, Folder 187)
    - no. 9680-9769, 1875 (Box 7, Folder 188)
    - no. 9770-9832, 1876, Jan.-Jun. (Box 7, Folder 189)
    - no. 9833-9864, 1876, Jul.-Dec. (Box 7, Folder 190)
    - no. 9865-9929, 1877, Jan.-Jun. (Box 7, Folder 191)
    - no. 9930-9971, 1878, Jan.-May (Box 7, Folder 192)
    - no. 9972-10012, 1878, Jun.-Dec. (Box 7, Folder 193)
    - no. 10013-10084, 1879, Jan.-Jun. (Box 7, Folder 194)
    - no. 10085-10135, 1879, Jul.-Sep. (Box 7, Folder 195)
    - no. 10136-10219, 1879, Oct.-Dec.; Undated (Box 7, Folder 196)
      Item 10199: Manuscript "The Moral Influence of the Kindergarten" by Elizabeth Peabody
    - no. 10220-10274, 1880, Jan.-Mar. (Box 7, Folder 197)
    - no. 10292-10309, 1880, Apr. (Box 7, Folder 198)
      April index number sequence out of order, index numbers for May: 10275-10291 in box 8 folder 199
    - no. 10275-10291, 1880, May (Box 8, Folder 199)
      May and April index number sequence out of order; April numbers: 10292-10309 in box 7 Folder 198
    - no. 10310-10450, 1880, Jun.-Dec.; Undated (Box 8, Folder 200)
      Items 10395-10432, 10334, and 10435 in folder 201
    - no. 10395-10462, 1881, Jan.-Jul. (Box 8, Folder 201)
      Items 10433, 10436-10450 in folder 200
    - no. 10463-10500, 1881, Aug.-Dec.; Undated (Box 8, Folder 202)
    - no. 10501-10541, 1882 (Box 8, Folder 203)
    - no. 10542-10588, 1883 (Box 8, Folder 204)
    - no. 10589-10653, 1884; Undated (Box 9, Folder 205)
    - no. 10654-10712, 1885 (Box 8, Folder 206)
    - no. 10713-10751, 1886 (Box 8, Folder 207)
    - no. 10752-10790, 1887, Jan.-Jun. (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - no. 10791-10823, 1887, Jul.-Dec. (Box 8, Folder 209)
    - no. 10824-10872, 1888 (Box 8, Folder 210)
    - no. 10873-10915, 1889, Jan.-Jun. (Box 8, Folder 211)
    - no. 10916-10962, 1889, Jul.-Dec. (Box 8, Folder 212)
    - no. 10963-11050, 1890, Jan.-Jun. (Box 8, Folder 213)
    - no. 11051-11090, 1890, Jul.-Oct. (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - no. 11091-11132, 1890, Nov.-Dec. (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - no. 11133-11191, 1891, Jan.-Mar. (Box 8, Folder 216)
    - no. 11192-11228, 1891, Apr.-Jun. (Box 8, Folder 217)
    - no. 11229-11288, 1891, Jul.-Dec. (Box 8, Folder 218)
    - no. 11289-11347, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 219)
    - no. 11348-11365, 1893 (Box 8, Folder 220)
    - no. 11366-11391, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 221)
      Item 11390: W.S. Monroe's outline of "Stanford Course: History of Education in California." Item 11391: Barnard bibliography
    - no. 11392-11405, 1895 (Box 8, Folder 222)
    - no. 11406-11450, 1896 (Box 8, Folder 223)
      For item 11421 see Series IV, Box 9, Folder 4
    - no. 11451-11497, 1897, Jan. 1-24 (Box 8, Folder 224)
    - no. 11498-11524, 1897, Jan. 25-31 (Box 8, Folder 225)
    - no. 11525-11579, 1897, Feb.-Jun. (Box 8, Folder 226)
    - no. 11580-11608, 1897, Jul.-Dec. (Box 8, Folder 227)
    - no. 11609-11677, 1898 (Box 8, Folder 228)
      Item 11609 through 11614 were not assigned index numbers in chronological order
    - no. 11678-11727, 1899 (Box 8, Folder 229)
      For items 11716, 11719, and 11720 see Series IV, Box 9, Folder 4
    - Various to H.B.; no. 11728-11756, Undated (Box 8, Folder 230)
      Includes letters from Charles H. Keyes, [N.] Pettie, Francis Plimpton, Gertrude [Edwards] (to Will Monroe), James Walker (to William Kent), Henry E. Burton, H.R. Burns, C.W. Eddy, J.H. Smart, Kate Sanborn, Frank E. King, William Eddy, Bradford K. Pierce, James D. Butler, G.H. Chensey, John G. Cunningham, A.F. Dutton, Edmund Dwight, M. G. McMahon, Louise R. Pollock, [Jane L.] Williams, H.B. Wilmerding, and A. Wilson. For items 11732 and 11729 see Series IV, Box 9, Folder 4. For Items 11740 and 11741 see Series IV, Box 9, Folder 5. For Items 11758, 11757, 11742, 11752, 11753 and 11751 see Series III, Box 9, Folder 13. For items 11746, 11747, 11754 See Series VI, Box 10, Folder 15.
    - Unidentified Fragments, 1822-1838, Undated (Box 8, Folder 231)
- Series II: Diaries, Notebooks, etc.
  - unspecified
    - Diaries, 1831, Apr.-May; 1833, Jan.-Feb.; 1835, Mar-Apr. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Official Memoranda, 1867 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - German Trip of Henry Barnard Jr.; French Notes, 1869, Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Family Geneology: Barnard, Bissell, Case, Seymour, Denison, Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Family Geneology, Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Series III: Writings, etc.
  - unspecified
    - Typed Extracts from Edward Hooker's Journal, 1805-1817 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Female Education, Undated; 1865 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      Includes "Seminar for Female Teachers and Teachers in Kindergarten" and "Higher Education for Girls at Berlin," both by unknown authors.
    - Typed Extracts from George Combe's Notes on the United States of North America During a Phrenological Visit in 1838-9-40, 1840 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Kindergarten, 1879, Nov 8; [1879], Undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Includes "Preamble and Resolutions of the Froebel Society of California," signed by E. Marwedel, K.E. Smett, and [Mrs.] Burton; "Religious Instruction in Kindergartens" by Mary Mann; "Report of Madame A. de Portugal, Inspection of the kindergartens of the [center] of Geneoa, Succinct expose of the system of Froebel;" and "Application of Kindergarten Principles to Graded Schools" by John Ogden
    - Wichard Lange's "Reminiscences", 1793-1853 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Stamped with index number: 2-3341
    - "Neglected Children," "Poverty," and "Unity of Life", Undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Unknown authors
    - Phi Beta Kappa Speech, Undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "Richard Edwards", Undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Unknown author
    - "Essay on the First Chapter of Genesis"; "Man is a Religious Nature", 1835, Undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
      First document is subtitled: "From an unprinted manuscript of Niederer, dictated to [Herm. Kruisi_jan]," second by unknown author.
    - Miscellaneous Speeches, etc., 1878, Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
      Index numbers 11758, 11757, 11742, 11752, 11753, 11751
- Series IV: Printed Material
  - unspecified
    - Clippings, Pamphlets, and Announcements, 1850-1881, (Bulk: 1850-1869) (Box 9, Folder 1)